Episode 13
第 13 集
Taste this.
尝尝这个。
I'm full. You need to eat too.
我饱了。 你也需要吃饭。
ma'am...
女士...
Something happened to Young Master Hua.
华少出事了。
I eat too much.
我吃太多了。
Excuse me for a moment.
请原谅我一下。
Why did he leave?
他为什么离开？
That's not important. You guys just keep going.
那不重要。 你们继续前进吧。
Stay here and watch it all.
留在这里观看这一切。
- Why did you leave? - What happen?
- 你为什么离开？ - 发生什么事？
It is nothing. Keep eating and drinking.
没什么。 继续吃喝。
Please bring another bottle of wine.
请再带一瓶酒。
Let's move on.
让我们继续。
What did my brother do this time?
这次哥哥做了什么？
Currently, Master Hwayoung...
目前，华阳大师...
It was in Concubine Mu's room.
是在穆妃的房间里。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
I don't know exactly.
我不太清楚。
The waiter came to report...
服务员过来汇报……
Master Hwayoung infiltrated...
华荣大师潜入...
To the room of Concubine Wu.
到了武妃的房间。
Sister, wake up.
姐姐，醒醒吧。
Check out Mu Yao.
看看穆瑶。
sisters.
姐妹。
Concubine Mu.
穆妃。
wake up.
醒来。
sisters!
姐妹！
Kian.
基安.
blood.
血。
What happen?
发生什么事？
Yao.
姚。
are you okay?
你还好吗？
Tuan.
团。
I'm doing great.
我很好。
Fortunately, Jisoo arrived on time...
庆幸的是，Jisoo准时到达了……
but...
但...
By mistake, Young Master Hua was injured.
误打误撞， 华少受伤了。
- teacher.
- 老师。
Calm down and listen to me.
冷静下来，听我说。
ma'am.
女士。
ma'am!
女士！
Is your wife okay?
你妻子还好吗？
Please show me your hands.
请让我看看你的手。
My hands are bleeding.
我的手在流血。
Huarongzhou.
华容洲。
- teacher. - Back off!
- 老师。 - 退后！
Sir, please listen to me.
先生，请听我说。
calm down. Let’s find out more...
冷静下来。 让我们了解更多...
Before doing something irreversible .
在做出不可挽回的事情之前 。
Please don't disturb me.
请不要打扰我。
Sir, don't kill him first.
先生，先别杀他。
How about we find out what's going on?
我们来看看发生了什么事怎么样？
Before punishing him?
在惩罚他之前？
Let's find out what happened?
我们来看看到底发生了什么？
Do you really not understand your brother’s personality?
你真的不了解你弟弟的性格吗？
No wonder you asked His Majesty...
怪不得你问陛下……
So I make Mu Yao my concubine.
所以我立慕瑶为妾。
It seems...
它似乎...
You and your brother have been planning this all along!
你和你哥哥 一直在计划这件事！
I know I lied to you many times ...
我知道我骗了你很多次 ...
So I don't blame you for not trusting me now.
所以 我不怪你现在不信任我。
But these are two different things.
但这是两件不同的事情。
- Sir, calm down... - I won't kill you...
- 先生，冷静点... - 我不会杀你...
But I'm going to cripple his arm...
但我要打断他的手臂...
So that he can learn to take care of his hands!
让他学会爱护自己的双手！
Kian.
基安.
Save me, Chen.
救救我，陈。
Aren't you moving?
你不动吗？
Kian.
基安.
Calm down, senior.
冷静点，前辈。
Looks like you want to fight me too.
看来你也想和我战斗啊。
What does mudamuda mean?
穆达姆达是什么意思？
Are you defending this useless person?
你是在维护这个没用的人吗？
Hua Shen was the only son of Chief Steward Hua.
华神 是华总管唯一的儿子。
I understand how you feel, sir.
我理解你的感受，先生。
However, be reasonable.
不过，要合理。
He treated my girl rudely today.
今天他 粗鲁地对待我的女儿。
It means that the person may be avoiding responsibility...
这意味着这个人可能在逃避责任......
Who is that person?
那个人是谁？
I'm not defending him.
我不是在为他辩护。
I think it's better...
我认为这样更好...
Put that person in jail first...
先把那个人关进监狱吧...
And wait until Judge Wang investigates.
等王法官 调查完毕。
There are more important things to do today.
今天还有更重要的事情要做。
Page...
页...
Judge Wang will not protect Hua Shen...
王法官 不会保护华神……
If you see him.
如果你看到他。
He got away easily.
他轻松地逃脱了。
What are you going to do?
你会怎样做？
Where will you take me?
你要带我去哪里？
Please help me, Qian.
请帮助我，钱。
Thank you to Teacher Young for your help.
感谢杨老师的帮助。
Go back home...
回家吧...
And treat your wounds.
并治疗你的伤口。
But there were many people in the front yard.
但前院里却有很多人。
Leave it to me.
交给我。
Take a break and come back again.
休息一下再回来。
See you again, Young Master.
又见面了，少爷。
ma'am.
女士。
are you okay?
你还好吗？
I'm doing great.
我很好。
Please forgive.
请原谅。
Madam, I'm sorry.
女士，对不起。
There is no need to apologize.
没有必要道歉。
good job. I have to thank you.
好工作。 我得谢谢你。
It doesn't seem weak.
看起来并不弱。
thank you.
谢谢。
See a therapist later.
稍后去看治疗师。
be careful.
当心。
I will help you.
我会帮你。
Bring this for him.
把这个拿给他。
Hang in there, madam.
坚持住，女士。
It really hurts.
真的很疼。
wait. Almost done.
等待。快完成了。
Hello, Young Master.
少爷您好。
- Young Master.
- 少爷。
let's do it.
我们开始做吧。
Teacher, why are you doing that...
老师，你为什么要这么做……
are you okay. Customers are well taken care of...
你还好吗。 顾客都被照顾得很好...
And they will be back as we speak.
在我们说话的时候他们就会回来。
Young Master, please let Yinxing do it.
少爷， 请让银星去做吧。
Not sure if I can do it?
不确定我是否能做到？
It's not like that.
不像那样。
It seems inappropriate to ask you to do this.
要求你这样做似乎不太合适。
Young Master, how about you make me faint...
少爷， 你让我晕倒怎么样……
Before treating the wound?
在处理伤口之前？
Low pain tolerance.
疼痛耐受力低。
Why are you protecting Hua Shen?
你为什么要保护华神？
After all, he is my brother.
毕竟，他是我的兄弟。
Is it very fast? I am new...
是不是很快？我是新的...
I kept hesitating...
我一直在犹豫...
But as you know, seniors need answers.
但如您所知， 老年人需要答案。
The teacher was very angry today.
今天老师很生气。
Young Master, aren’t you angry?
少爷，你不生气吗？
Why should I be angry?
我为什么要生气？
Why is Young Master helping me?
少爷为何要帮我？
You're not trying to test me, are you?
你不会是想考验我吧？
You keep my secrets...
你保守我的秘密...
Save it.
保存。
We are on the same side now.
我们现在是站在同一边的。
Is that person so boring...
那个人这么无聊吗...
Until he has to say Who does he respect?
直到他不得不说 他尊重谁？
great. I'm going.
伟大的。我要去。
ma'am.
女士。
When I went to the doctor to ask for medicine...
当我去找医生要药时...
I saw bodyguard Hua take out a medicine bottle...
只见华保镖拿出一个药瓶……
And then he hurried out.
然后他就匆匆出去了。
I said hello, but he didn't even notice me.
我打招呼，但 他根本没有注意到我。
I wonder what the wound is like.
我想知道伤口是什么样的。
When you return...
你什么时候回来...
I saw him standing at the door.
我看到他站在门口。
Was he hurt too?
他也受伤了吗？
I do not know.
我不知道。
I didn't look closely.
我没仔细看。
I fell on a chair...
我摔倒在椅子上...
And it was definitely scratched.
而且肯定是被划伤了。
Tsuiju.
翠菊。
Check out Huang Rongzhou.
看看黄荣洲。
What's the problem?
有什么问题？
Normally, I'm always happy...
平时我总是很高兴...
Take the opportunity to access Rongzhou .
趁机访问容州 。
But not today.
但不是今天。
Maybe he was worried about her.
也许他是担心她。
Save your medicine.
保存你的药。
Madam, can you feel it...
女士，你能感觉到吗...
Does Young Master treat you differently?
少爷对你有什么不同吗？
Of course he treated me differently.
当然， 他对我的态度是不同的。
What will you do, wife?
老婆你会怎么做？
You don't understand.
你不明白。
That person treats me like that...
那个人这样对我...
Because I know the secret.
因为我知道这个秘密。
secret?
秘密？
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Secret. How should I say it?
秘密。 我该怎么说呢？
Kian.
基安.
What does the teacher say?
老师怎么说？
I never had a chance to meet Mr. Lee.
我一直没有机会见到李先生。
Yesterday, mom asked your dad.
昨天，妈妈 问你爸爸。
They said Master sent your younger brother...
他们说是师父派你弟弟来的……
Ke Yamen...
柯衙门...
above...
多于...
About that shameful behavior.
关于这种可耻的行为。
He can't interfere...
他不能干涉……
When the incident comes to light.
当事件曝光后。
So we need your help to learn more.
因此， 我们需要您的帮助来了解更多信息。
- I have a plan. - That's not enough.
- 我有个计划。 - 这还不够。
Your brother never suffered.
你的兄弟从未受过苦。
How will he survive in prison?
他将如何 在监狱中生存？
How can he survive?
他该如何生存？
I won't just sit still...
我不会坐以待毙...
But we need to find the root cause of the problem...
但我们需要找到问题的根本原因......
Before finding a solution.
在找到解决方案之前。
Mom isn't there...
妈妈不在...
Yesterday when he was taken away.
昨天他被带走的时候。
Why didn't you stop them?
你为什么不阻止他们？
He is your only brother.
他是你唯一的兄弟。
When your mom was pregnant with you...
当你妈妈怀着你的时候...
I touch my mom's belly every day...
我每天都摸妈妈的肚子
And he said he would protect you...
他还说他会保护你...
After you were born.
你出生之后。
Now he's in trouble...
现在他遇到麻烦了...
But are you just sitting here?
但你只是坐在这里吗？
Mother, don't worry.
妈妈，别担心。
If something truly unfair happened to my sister...
如果真的有什么不公平的事发生在我妹妹身上的话……
I won't stay still.
我不会保持静止。
You have never been to prison.
你从来没有进过监狱。
How do we know who framed him?
我们怎么知道是谁陷害了他？
My mother asked Judge Wang for help...
我妈妈向王法官求助……
But he wouldn't let me in.
但他不让我进去。
He said his mother would be able to visit him in a few days.
他说他的母亲几天后就能来看他。
How many more days?
还有几天？
Your brother won't survive prison.
你的兄弟在监狱里活不下去。
He will suffer.
他会受苦。
What happened in this house...
这间屋子里发生了什么……
And you are Mr.'s wife.
而你是先生的妻子。
Mom feels...
妈妈感觉...
The judge will not prevent you from entering.
法官不会阻止您进入。
My brother was just taken...
我弟弟刚刚被带走了...
And I don't know yet...
而且我还不知道...
What actually happened yesterday?
昨天究竟发生了什么？
What good will it do me if I go to jail now?
如果我现在进监狱对我有什么好处？
So what can you do while sitting here?
那么 你坐在这里能做什么呢？
Mom knows...
妈妈知道...
You always think you're embarrassed...
你总 觉得自己很丢脸
And it's not you who suffer in prison...
而且在监狱里受苦的不是你......
Therefore, it is natural that you are not anxious.
所以，你不着急也是理所当然的。
I think he's embarrassed?
我觉得他很尴尬？
To be more precise, his inappropriate behavior was...
更准确地说， 他的不当行为是……
It makes us feel ashamed.
这让我们感到羞愧。
It's true that I haven't been there yet.
确实我还没去过。
But why be anxious?
但为什么要焦虑呢？
Making a big fuss...
搞个大闹……
Before solving the problem...
在解决问题之前...
It only makes us vulnerable.
它只会让我们变得脆弱。
Mother, how can you be sure that he is innocent?
妈妈，你怎么能确定他是无辜的呢？
Maybe he deserves it...
也许他应得的...
His current situation.
他现在的处境。
Since I came here...
自从我来到这里...
Mom can't stop talking...
妈妈说得停不下来
How much my brother will suffer in prison.
我的兄弟 在监狱里要受多少苦啊。
Did you see that my hand was hurt?
你看到我的手受伤了吗？
And ask about it?
并询问此事？
- Mom... - That's it.
- 妈妈... - 就是这样。
My mother always takes my brother's side...
我妈妈总是站在我弟弟一边...
And I got used to it.
我已经习惯了。
If you don't get a proper answer from me...
如果你没有从我这里得到正确的答案......
I don't think mom will let me go easily .
我想妈妈不会轻易放过我的 。
Now let's go to jail.
现在我们去监狱吧。
Find out who framed your sister .
找出谁陷害了你的妹妹 。
Madam, you said something hurtful
女士，你说了一些伤人的话
I had too much trouble choosing my words carefully.
我很难仔细地选择我的措辞。
First, let's get Shen out of jail.
首先，让沉出狱。
Pengadilan Yellow Blue
Pengadilan黄蓝
Here it is.
这里是。
Kian.
基安.
Qian, I was waiting...
钱，我在等……
All day.
一整天。
Don't you understand what's going on?
你不明白这是怎么回事吗？
I worked really hard to get in here.
我真的很努力才来到这里。
My mother is not allowed in.
我妈妈不准进去。
Are you here to take me out? Isn't that right?
你是来带我出去的吗？ 是不是这样？
It's not that easy, brother.
这并不容易，兄弟。
I've said it many times.
我已经说过很多次了。
Mu Yao is not someone you can touch.
慕瑶不是你可以碰触的人。
Why don't you listen to me?
你为什么不听我的？
I remember everything you said.
你说的一切我都记得。
I won't touch anyone you tell me not to.
我 不会碰任何你告诉我不要碰的人。
Why don't you trust me?
你为什么不相信我？
So what happened yesterday?
那么昨天发生了什么？
Why did I come to Mu Yao's room...
我为什么会来到慕瑶的房间……
With dirty clothes?
带着脏衣服？
I really don't know.
我真的不知道。
I drank too much yesterday.
我昨天喝太多了。
I tried to regain consciousness in the backyard.
我 试图在后院恢复意识。
One of your servants reminded me...
你的一位仆人 提醒我...
To stay there.
留在那里。
So I stayed in the pavilion.
于是我就留在了亭子里。
so?
所以？
Then I...
然后我...
Looks like you want to stay here...
看来你想留在这里...
A few more days.
还有几天。
I will say
我会说
I saw a beautiful maid in the backyard...
我在后院看到了一个漂亮的女仆……
And he seduced me.
他勾引了我。
I'm drunk...
我醉了...
So I followed him somewhere.
于是我 就跟着他去了某个地方。
Soon after, I lost consciousness.
不久之后， 我就失去了知觉。
When I woke up, I saw you in front of me.
当我醒来时， 我看到你在我面前。
I'm so scared I can't speak. me...
我害怕得说不出话来。 我...
Are you sure the maid seduced you?
你确定是女仆勾引你的吗？
He kept spying on me.
他一直在监视我。
Doesn't that mean he likes me?
那不是说明他喜欢我吗？
You are so confident!
你真有信心啊！
I drank too much alcohol...
我喝了太多酒...
And act according to your physical desires.
并根据你的身体欲望行事。
But you excuse yourself.
但你 原谅自己。
No one can control themselves when they are drunk.
没有人一喝醉就控制不住自己。
I think my assessment is correct...
我认为我的评价是正确的...
Affected by excessive alcohol.
受过量饮酒影响。
So I think he's interested in me...
所以我 觉得他对我感兴趣...
And I broke in by mistake ...
而且我不小心 闯入了...
To someone's residence...
到某人的住处...
And it looks like a pervert.
而且看起来就像是一个变态。
Qian, it's not my fault.
钱，这不是我的错。
You said it with conviction.
你说的很有说服力。
It looks okay...
看起来还可以...
Although our mothers say it differently.
尽管我们的母亲说法不同。
In that case...
在这种情况下...
Stay here and repent for a few more days.
留在这里，再 忏悔几天。
Kian.
基安.
Save me, Chen.
救救我，陈。
This place is dirty and smells really bad.
这个地方很脏而且气味很难闻。
There are also rats.
还有老鼠。
The guards tortured me.
恶警们对我进行酷刑。
I don't think I can last a few more days .
我想我撑不了几天了。
Kian.
基安.
Is it true?
这是真的吗？
A wound on my head...
我头上有伤口...
It healed well.
痊愈得很好。
I don't think you were tortured.
我不认为你受到折磨。
- I... - Learn from this.
- 我... - 从中​​学习。
Kian!
基安！
Kian.
基安.
How is your sister?
你妹妹好吗？
I warned him many times...
我警告过他很多次了...
But his physical desires...
但他的肉体欲望……
Always master.
永远是主人。
This time...
这次...
He even did that in your house.
他甚至 在你家里也这么做了。
He deserves to be beaten.
他活该被打。
You think too...
你也觉得...
Is that person the criminal?
那人是罪犯吗？
Kian.
基安.
your sister...
你妹妹...
It's quite immoral...
实在是太不道德了...
But that person did...
但那个人却...
Because he was drunk.
因为他喝醉了。
That person is my only son...
那个人是我唯一的儿子……
And you only have one brother.
而你只有一个兄弟。
Even if you get angry at me...
就算你对我生气...
You can't leave him in trouble .
你不能让他陷入麻烦 。
my beloved daughter
我心爱的女儿
Why should I be angry?
我为什么要生气？
I don't think he did that.
我不认为他这么做了。
Is it true?
这是真的吗？
Hello, madam.
你好女士。
You are my servant. No format required.
你是我的仆人。 无需格式。
I have a few questions .
我有几个问题 。
Have you seen anything strange...?
你有看到什么奇怪的东西吗...？
The day you went to look for my sister?
你去找我妹妹的那天？
I went to the backyard...
我去了后院...
Muda Hua was sitting alone...
穆达华独自坐着……
In the pavilion.
亭内。
They say the servant left...
他们说仆人离开了...
Buy him some hangover soup.
给他买点醒酒汤。
What he said was...
他说的是……
After I deliver my message?
我发出消息后？
He said he drank too much...
他说他喝多了...
And I want to rest there.
我想在那里休息。
He asked me to tell Mrs. Hua...
他让我转告华太太……
Coming to the pavilion to look for him...
来亭子找他……
After the banquet was over.
宴会结束后。
Who did you tell that he was in the pavilion?
你告诉谁他在亭子里？
no.
不。
Did you meet someone on your way home?
你在回家的路上遇到什么人了吗？
I haven't met anyone.
我还没有遇到任何人。
ma'am.
女士。
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
It has nothing to do with you.
这与你无关。
Don't think too much about it. Go and rest.
别想太多。 去休息吧。
Madam, what is Cuizhu doing?
夫人，翠竹在做什么呢？
There is nothing. I'm just sure...
没有什么。我只是确定...
To make myself calm.
为了让自己平静。
Where does Mu Yao live now?
慕瑶现在住在哪里？
same as before...
和之前一样...
But it has been renovated.
但已经重新装修过。
good.
好的。
ma'am.
女士。
The teacher got angry last time...
上次老师生气了...
So he's a bit over the top.
所以他有点过分了。
You may have suffered serious injuries.
您可能受了重伤。
You don't have to be awake.
你不必醒着。
Go back to your room and rest.
回到自己的房间休息吧。
I'm doing great.
我很好。
What are you guys doing?
你们在干什么？
ma'am.
女士。
The Lord has commanded us to take care...
主吩咐我们要小心……
Your concubine's residence.
你妾的住处。
No one can enter.
任何人都不能进入。
you...
你...
Please tell Mu Yao that I am coming. He will let me in.
请告诉慕瑶我来了。 他会让我进去。
Please, ma'am.
请，女士。
Please wait outside.
请在外面等候。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
You were waiting for me, right?
你一直在等我，对吗？
If you come to defend Hua Shen...
如果你来保卫华神的话……
Shouldn’t we be humble?
难道我们不应该谦虚吗？
My brother is innocent.
我的兄弟是无辜的。
Why should I defend him?
我为什么要为他辩护？
Mu Yao, it's just the two of us now.
慕瑶，现在就我们两个人了。
Let’s get straight to the point.
让我们开门见山吧。
I think...
我认为...
I wouldn't use such a cunning method ...
我才不会用这么狡猾的方法呢 ……
After being locked up before.
之前被关起来之后。
I realized I was wrong.
我意识到我错了。
I'm really disappointed.
我真的很失望。
I didn't mean to come here...
我不是故意来这里的...
But I think I have to do my part...
但我想我必须尽自己的一份力量...
In your play...
在你的戏里...
Don't let your hard work go to waste.
不要让你的辛劳白费。
I told you I wouldn't compete with you anymore...
我说过我不会再和你竞争了...
Demi Jong-ye is...
黛米钟业是...
But you don't believe me.
但你不相信我。
You even used a cunning method...
你还用了狡猾的手段……
And used it to get rid of me.
并 用它来摆脱我。
Do you think I'm doing this for him?
你认为我这样做是为了他吗？
What else?
还有什么？
You framed Hua Shen.
你陷害了华神。
This time I won't stand still.
这次我不会再坐以待毙了。
Every injustice has a perpetrator.
每一个不公正现象都有一个肇事者。
I am patient with you...
我对你很有耐心...
Because I regret what I did to you.
因为我 后悔我对你所做的事。
But now you're implicating innocent people...
但现在你却 连累了无辜的人......
Using cunning means.
使用狡猾的手段。
I will never be generous again.
我再也不会慷慨了。
Every injustice has a perpetrator.
每一个不公正现象都有一个肇事者。
Hua Chen.
华晨.
How dare you say that?
你怎么敢这么说？
Why can't I say that ?
为什么我不能这么说 ？
Tuan.
团。
Judge Wang sent more people.
王判官又派了更多的人。
This is related to the Hua Shen incident.
这和华神事件有关。
They want to ask Mu-cheop a question.
他们想问Mu-cheop一个问题。
Should we make them wait outside like before?
我们应该像以前一样让他们在外面等吗？
Let it wait.
让它等待吧。
All right.
好的。
wait.
等待。
Let me ask you first.
我先问你一下。
Your family are selfish people...
你的家人都是自私的人...
A person who cannot distinguish between right and wrong.
一个无法辨别是非的人。
You said Hua Shen was innocent, right?
你说华神是无辜的吧？
You were the one who prepared the banquet incident, right?
宴会事件就是你准备的吧？
I really question my brother's morality...
我真的很怀疑我弟弟的道德……
But he never...
但他从来不...
You have bad intentions.
你有不良意图。
Is it true?
这是真的吗？
I can't guarantee anything else, but...
我不能保证其他任何事情，但是...
I can tell you that he has never lied to me.
我可以告诉你，他 从来没有骗过我。
I warned him many times ...
我警告过他很多次了 ...
And he always respected my requests.
而且他总是 尊重我的要求。
In the end, you...
最后，你...
I have known you for a long time.
我认识你很久了。
You are a person who does not shed tears easily .
你是一个不轻易流泪的人 。
That day, you were curled up in the corner of your room...
那天，你 蜷缩在房间的角落里……
Trembling with fear.
恐惧得发抖。
It's just acting.
这只是演戏而已。
Your intentions are clear.
你的意图很明确。
You are right.
你是对的。
I locked him up.
我把他锁了起来。
Hua Shen didn't touch me at all .
华神根本没有碰我 。
I heard the news that the servant died...
我听到仆人去世的消息……
A few days ago at Hua Residence...
前几天在华公馆...
But Mr. Hwa appeared at the banquet...
但华先生却出现在宴会上……
Without any indication of the outcome.
没有任何结果的迹象。
Head Servant Hwa acts as a shield for the family.
首席仆人华 充当家庭的盾牌。
Of course you guys aren't there...
当然你们都不在...
Who cares about the life of a servant?
谁会关心仆人的死活呢？
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Waiter commits suicide
服务员自杀
This is Linglong.
这是玲珑。
Your father told us to buy this.
你父亲叫我们买这个。
The young lady has reached marriageable age.
这位年轻女士已经到了适婚年龄。
So you need to get dressed.
所以你需要穿好衣服。
Look at the jewels.
看看珠宝。
Very beautiful.
很漂亮。
do you like
你喜欢
I'll give it to you.
我把它给你。
I am a waiter.
我是一名服务员。
How can I use this precious thing?
这么珍贵的东西我该如何使用呢？
Why not?
为什么不？
This one.
这个。
That's inappropriate.
那是不合适的。
Put it in.
把它放进去。
It's right for you.
这很适合你。
He said he had reached marriageable age.
他说他已经到了结婚的年龄。
But you are one year older than me.
但你比我大一岁。
This hairpin will be your dowry.
这个发夹 将作为你的嫁妆。
dowry?
嫁妆？
Nona...
诺娜...
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It won't run.
它不会运行。
Linglong lost his parents when he was young...
玲珑年幼时就失去了父母……
And he grew up with me in the North.
他和我一起在北方长大。
You remember him, right?
你还记得他，对吧？
Some are more beautiful.
有些更漂亮。
Go ahead and try it. Cheers.
继续尝试。干杯。
The servant was once a criminal.
仆人曾经是一个罪犯。
He is an orphan...
他是一个孤儿...
And I have no family.
而且我没有家人。
My father was scolded...
爸爸被骂了...
Stealing property...
盗窃财物...
And isolated.
并且孤立。
All the servants in my house...
我家所有的仆人...
For sale.
出售。
Still a slave...
依旧是奴隶……
Wherever it is sold.
哪里有卖的。
At first I thought so too.
一开始我也是这么想的。
but...
但...
Why Hua Shen...
为何华神...
Who bought it?
谁买的？
dare!
敢！
- You will beat me! - Hwa sister...
- 你会打败我的！ - 华姐...
Stop...
停止...
I pity him.
我可怜他。
How ungrateful.
多么忘恩负义。
You should thank your lucky stars...
你应该感谢你的幸运星...
Because my friend likes you.
因为我朋友喜欢你。
How dare you refuse...
你怎么敢拒绝...
Did you even hit Huang?
你还打黄吗？
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
I was wrong.
我错了。
I'm sorry, husband.
对不起，丈夫。
Are you my concubine?
你是我的妾吗？
My concubine?
我的妾？
I don't consider you my concubine.
我不把你当我的妾。
You lowly slave...
你这个卑贱的奴隶...
And I bought you!
我还买了你！
You get angry easily, don't you?
你很容易生气，不是吗？
good. I am a good person...
好的。我是好人...
Well, I'll leave it to you this time.
好吧，这次就交给你了。
Now pack your bags...
现在收拾行李...
And go with Tuan Wang.
并与团王同去。
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
my husband...
我的老公...
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
I mean, from now on you are mine.
我的意思是， 从现在起你就是我的了。
It really is.
确实如此。
my husband.
我的老公。
A woman cannot serve two husbands.
一个女人 不能同时侍奉两个丈夫。
How can you hand me over?
你怎么能把我交给我？
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
You are just a lowly servant!
你只是一个卑微的仆人！
I can hand you over to anyone!
我可以把你交给任何人！
are you okay.
你还好吗。
My home is like his home.
我的家就像他的家一样。
I will treat you well.
我会好好待你的。
If you don't want to, that's okay.
如果您不想，也没关系。
Take this. I'll sell you to a brothel!
拿着它。 我要把你卖到妓院！
Do you want me to do that?
你想让我这么做吗？
Oh no.
不好了。
Even though I'm a slave...
虽然我是奴隶...
I can't stand such humiliation !
我受不了这样的羞辱 ！
Selir Linglong.
塞利尔玲珑。
Selir Linglong!
瑟利尔玲珑！
so...
所以...
Hua Chen...
华晨...
What makes you confident?
是什么让你充满自信？
Hua Shen is innocent?
华神是无辜的？
Insignificant servant...
微不足道的仆人...
The person who died in Hwataek...
在华泽死去的人……
The person I consider my older brother.
我认为是我哥哥的人。
- I... - What?
- 我... - 什么？
What do you want to say?
你想说什么？
Hua Chen.
华晨.
I'm giving you a chance. I'm giving you time.
我给你一个机会。 我给你时间。
But what do you do?
但你做什么呢？
As you know...
如你所知...
Linglong and I are very close.
我和玲珑的关系很亲密。
Do you think you made up for it?
你觉得你弥补了吗？
By making me Jong Ye-ran's concubine?
让我成为钟艺兰的小妾？
I didn't know that the maid was Linglong ...
没想到那个侍女竟然是玲珑 ……
I also ask your Excellency...
我还 请教阁下...
Do you consider yourself an ordinary servant?
你认为自己是一个普通的仆人吗？
So please be quiet...
所以请安静...
And will you hand over Hua Shen to your father?
而你会把华神交给你的父亲吗？
You know Steward Hu will protect him...
你知道胡管家 会保护他的……
But you're still doing that.
但你仍然这样做。
The reason is in your eyes...
原因就在你的眼里……
The life of an anonymous server is very precious.
匿名服务器的生命 是非常宝贵的。
You said you'd never hurt me again...
你说过你不会再伤害我了...
And I almost believed you.
我几乎相信你了。
I want to believe it...
我愿意相信...
You may not be involved in our family's affairs.
我们家的事情你不可以插手。
But what happened to Linglong...
可是 玲珑到底怎么了……
I realized I will never forgive you .
我意识到我永远不会原谅你 。
Many people are having difficulties...
很多人都遇到了困难...
In the hands of the Hua family...
在华家手中……
And it doesn't come true.
但这并没有实现。
You are part of the Hua family.
你是华家的一员。
It makes you indifferent and selfish.
它让你变得 冷漠和自私。
You can pretend not to know...
你可以假装不知道...
Because I didn't see it...
因为我没看到...
But I can't.
但我不能。
So you framed him?
所以你陷害了他？
To avenge Linglong?
为玲珑报仇？
Because you didn't punish him...
因为你没有惩罚他...
I made sure he got his reward.
我确保他 得到了奖励。
You are not interested in the lives of your servants.
你对仆人的生活不感兴趣。
What about me, Concubine Jong Ye?
那我 琼妃呢？
Could it cost him a fortune?
难道这要花他一大笔钱吗？
By doing this?
通过做这个？
Do you take advantage of a man who loves you?
你会利用一个爱你的男人吗？
Why can't I do that?
为什么我不能这样做？
That means we must accept all evil ...
这意味着我们必须接受一切邪恶 ......
What the Hwa family did...
华氏家族做了什么……
Without a fight?
不战而屈人之兵？
For me...
为我...
As long as you're against family...
只要你反对家人...
It is merely a means to an end.
它只是达到目的的一种手段。
great.
伟大的。
I understand.
我明白。
ma'am.
女士。
Madam, what's going on?
女士，这是怎么回事？
am...
是...
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
From now on, without my permission...
从现在开始，未经我的允许...
You cannot enter Yao 's house .
你不能进姚家。
If Muda Muda doesn't stop you that day ...
如果穆达穆达那天不阻止你的话......
Will your sword cut me down?
你的剑会砍倒我吗？
It's true, right?
这是真的，对吧？
Jong Ye-ran.
钟艺兰.
Are jade pendants that important?
翡翠吊坠有那么重要吗？
Does it really matter who that person is?
这个人是谁真的很重要吗？
Who is standing with you in the temple?
谁和你一起站在圣殿里？
When you were young?
你小时候？
Are romantic feelings possible ?
浪漫的感情可能吗 ？
Just remembering someone ...
只是想起一个人 ...
The person you gave the jade pendant to?
你把玉佩送给了谁？
Why am I saying this now?
我为什么现在说这个？
Just curious...
只是好奇...
Is it true that he is a liar?
他真的是骗子吗？
You can't gain someone else's trust...
你无法获得别人的信任...
And improve the situation.
并改善现状。
Even if you sacrifice your life...
哪怕牺牲自己的生命...
I didn't even have time to defend myself...
我连保护自己的时间都没有……
When you draw a sword on me .
当你向我拔剑时 。
Am I showing weakness...
我是不是表现出软弱了……
Are you trying to manipulate me into freeing Hua Shen?
你是想操纵我 释放华神吗？
great...
伟大的...
If you think that way about me too.
如果你也这么想我的话。
ma'am.
女士。
Dia menyukai Qianzhi.
Dia menyukai Qianzhi.
What are you going to do with Hua Shen?
你要拿华神做什么？
I leave it to you.
我把它留给你。
Tuan.
团。
King Hakim's men have not left yet.
哈基姆国王的人 还没有离开。
What should I say to them this time?
这次我该对他们说什么？
Find the reason and kick them out.
找出原因，把他们踢出去。
All right.
好的。
Adigan Bonus
阿迪甘奖金
Internal damage appears to be serious.
内部损坏看来很严重。
Why do I only want Jindao powder?
为什么我只想要金岛粉？
I'll check it.
我会检查一下。
Don't bother. Just give me Jindao powder.
别打扰。 给我金岛粉就行了。
hurry up, please.
请快点。
But, you don't seem to experience...
但是， 你似乎没有经历过...
external wounds.
外部伤口。
Jindao powder is only good for external wounds.
金刀粉只对外伤有好处。
Haven't found it yet?
还没找到吗？
I am looking for it.
我正在寻找它。
this. Where is the pain?
这。哪里痛？
We will treat your wounds.
我们会治疗你的伤口。
Why are you in a hurry?
你为什么这么着急？
Doctor, do you have Jindao powder?
医生，有金岛粉吗？
What happen? Who got hurt?
发生什么事？ 谁受伤了？
Why does everyone want Jin Dao powder?
为什么大家都 想要金岛粉？
please give it to me This is an emergency situation.
请给我 这是紧急情况。